<add xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" overwrite="true">
<doc>
<field name="uri">http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Accordionist</field>
<field name="entity_type">paintings</field>
<field name="timestamp">NOW</field>
<field name="sameAs">http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/The_Accordionist</field>
<field name="sameAs">http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Accordionist</field>
<field name="sameAs">http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q7712224</field>
<field name="sameAs">http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.0gk__xx</field>
<field name="subject" update="add">http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Paintings_by_Pablo_Picasso</field>
<field name="subject" update="add">http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1911_paintings</field>
<field name="subject" update="add">http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Guggenheim_Museum</field>
<field name="subject" update="add">http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Paintings_of_people</field>
<field name="subject" update="add">http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Cubist_paintings</field>
<field name="subject" update="add">http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Accordionists</field>
<field name="abstract">The Accordionist is a 1911 painting by Pablo Picasso. As stated by the title, the painting is meant to portray a man playing an accordion. The division of three-dimensional forms into a two-dimensional plane indicate that the painting is in the style of analytic cubism, which was developed by Picasso and Georges Braque between 1907 and 1914. The onset of cubism is possibly due to Picasso and Braque rebelling against centuries of traditional, realistic art that imitates the natural world. In earlier stages of analytic cubism, such as Picasso's Carafe, Jug and Fruit Bowl, Picasso begins to break up the subject matter and alter the sense of depth. However, in earlier work there is still a defined sense of the subject's shape and volume. The picture plane is distorted, but not to the same extent as later paintings such as The Accordionist which verge on complete abstraction. Also differentiating early and late analytical cubsim is the use of color. In Carafe, Jug and Fruit Bowl Picasso uses color to define the table cloth, bowls, and fruit, allowing the viewer to easily discern the subject matter, despite the slight flattening and separation of the picture plane. The Accordionist on the other hand is almost monochromatic which further camouflages the subject.</field>
<field name="label">The Accordionist</field>
<field name="comment">The Accordionist is a 1911 painting by Pablo Picasso. As stated by the title, the painting is meant to portray a man playing an accordion. The division of three-dimensional forms into a two-dimensional plane indicate that the painting is in the style of analytic cubism, which was developed by Picasso and Georges Braque between 1907 and 1914. The onset of cubism is possibly due to Picasso and Braque rebelling against centuries of traditional, realistic art that imitates the natural world.</field>
<field name="name"/>
<field name="artist">http://dbpedia.org/resource/Pablo_Picasso</field>
<field name="city">http://dbpedia.org/resource/United_States</field>
<field name="city">http://dbpedia.org/resource/New_York_City</field>
<field name="museum">http://dbpedia.org/resource/Solomon_R._Guggenheim_Museum</field>
<field name="title">The Accordionist</field>
<field name="type">Oil on canvas</field>
<field name="isPrimaryTopicOf">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Accordionist</field>
<field name="photo-collection">http://wifo5-03.informatik.uni-mannheim.de/flickrwrappr/photos/The_Accordionist</field>
</doc>
<doc>
<field name="uri">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Accordionist</field>
<field name="entity_type">paintings</field>
<field name="timestamp">NOW</field>
<field name="primaryTopic">http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Accordionist</field>
</doc>
<doc>
<field name="uri">http://wikidata.dbpedia.org/resource/Q7712224</field>
<field name="entity_type">paintings</field>
<field name="timestamp">NOW</field>
<field name="sameAs">http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Accordionist</field>
</doc>
</add>
