<add xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" overwrite="true">
<doc>
<field name="uri">http://dbpedia.org/resource/Apocalypse_in_Lilac,_Capriccio</field>
<field name="entity_type">paintings</field>
<field name="timestamp">NOW</field>
<field name="sameAs">http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Apocalypse_in_Lilac,_Capriccio</field>
<field name="sameAs">http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q4780090</field>
<field name="sameAs">http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.09v4sky</field>
<field name="sameAs">http://dbpedia.org/resource/Apocalypse_in_Lilac,_Capriccio</field>
<field name="subject" update="add">http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1945_paintings</field>
<field name="subject" update="add">http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Paintings_by_Marc_Chagall</field>
<field name="abstract">Apocalypse en Lilas, Capriccio is a 1945 gouache painting by the Russian-born artist Marc Chagall. The 20-inch by 14-inch work was created by Chagall in response to the devastation brought by the Holocaust; its imagery consists of a crucified Jew - upper half male to reflect the attempted genocide of European Jewry and the lower half female to reflect his recently died wife in the image of a classic crucifixion representation of Jesus Christ looking down in sadness at a Nazi storm trooper while other acts of violence – another crucifixion, a man being hanged and an adult male stabbing a child – can be seen in the background while an inverted clock falls out of the sky. The work is hugely important within the oeuvre of Chagall's work as it is most likely the witnessing of the horrors of the concentration camps, that were being broadcast daily in NY / USA as the American troops were liberating the concentration camps in March, April and May 1945, that stimulated him to return to his work following his cessation in respect of the death of his beloved wife Bella in September 1944. The work is iconic and deeply personal as he addresses this crucifixion in a unique fashion no doubt befitting the emotion of the moment. The composition reflects his grief for both the unimaginable horrors and mass murder on a scale unknown to modern man of Europe's Jewry represented by a naked man adorned by his Talit and Tefillin. The lower part feminine reflects his mourning and tribute to his late wife Bella. This is equally the only example where he represented the 'crucified' naked with only his religious adornments. Equally there are no other examples where Chagall carefully included a Nazi storm trooper as a central identifiable figure but to ensure clarity he added a wolf like tail. The representation of the right hand side of the image is telling. The working man holds the woman (no doubt his wife)in the air by her legs - representing that the woman is the lifeline of the Jewish people as the religion of children is dictated by the mother's faith rather than the father's - and it is she that is holding the holy 'Torah' in the air to try and save it (and the religion) by reaching the safety of the floating clock used much by Chagall before and after. The position of the Torah just touching the edge of the clock and no more is likely to convey Chagall's (and the world's) understandable fear the Nazi regime may have succeeded in their evil 'final solution'. Chagall kept the painting in his personal collection. It was initially sold by the artist’s son in 1985 to a private collector in France. In October 2009, it was purchased by Ben Uri the London Jewish Museum of Art ~ The Art Museum for Everyone ~ based in Boundary Road, off Abbey Road, St John's Wood, London NW8 0RH for US$43,000, despite estimates after the historical context correctly understood and researched by Ben Uri was released and recognised by the international community that it could be worth more than $1.5 million, and was publicly displayed for the first time in January 2010.</field>
<field name="label">Apocalypse in Lilac, Capriccio</field>
<field name="comment">Apocalypse en Lilas, Capriccio is a 1945 gouache painting by the Russian-born artist Marc Chagall.</field>
<field name="isPrimaryTopicOf">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apocalypse_in_Lilac,_Capriccio</field>
<field name="photo-collection">http://wifo5-03.informatik.uni-mannheim.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Apocalypse_in_Lilac,_Capriccio</field>
</doc>
<doc>
<field name="uri">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apocalypse_in_Lilac,_Capriccio</field>
<field name="entity_type">paintings</field>
<field name="timestamp">NOW</field>
<field name="primaryTopic">http://dbpedia.org/resource/Apocalypse_in_Lilac,_Capriccio</field>
</doc>
<doc>
<field name="uri">http://wikidata.dbpedia.org/resource/Q4780090</field>
<field name="entity_type">paintings</field>
<field name="timestamp">NOW</field>
<field name="sameAs">http://dbpedia.org/resource/Apocalypse_in_Lilac,_Capriccio</field>
</doc>
</add>
